Guide to the Oleg Jardetzky Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Oleg Jardetzky papers
1957-2003
SC0825
Jardetzky, Oleg.
58.5 Linear feet
Collection includes papers from his years at Harvard, 1957-67; records from the Dept. of Molecular Pharmacology at Stanford and the Stanford Magnetic Resonance Laboratory, 1970-2001; and papers pertaining to his other professional activities, including the International Conference on Magnetic Resonance in Biological Systems (1964-2002), the International Society for Magnetic Resonance, and the World Federation of Scientists and the Ettore Majorana Centre for Scientific Culture (1988-2003).
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
Access: boxes 14-16 are not open to research use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Jardetzky earned his M.D. at the University of Minnesota Medical School in 1954 and his Ph.D. in physiology and physical chemistry at University of Minnesota in 1956. He was on the faculty of the Harvard Medical School from 1957 to 1966 and was then a director at the Merck Institute for Therapeutic Research before joining the faculty at Stanford's School of Medicine in 1969. He was director of the Stanford Magnetic Resonance Laboratory from 1975 to 1997. He has held a large number of visiting appointments and served as chairman of a number of professional committees, boards and conferences, including directing several institutes held at the Ettore Majorana Centre for Scientific Culture in Erice, Sicily. His research interests include structural basis of pharmacological action, biological signal processing, and fundamentals of drug design.
Description of the Collection
Collection includes papers from his years at Harvard, 1957-67; records from the Dept. of Molecular Pharmacology at Stanford and the Stanford Magnetic Resonance Laboratory, 1970-2001; and papers pertaining to his other professional activities, including the International Conference on Magnetic Resonance in Biological Systems (1964-2002), the International Society for Magnetic Resonance, and the World Federation of Scientists and the Ettore Majorana Centre for Scientific Culture (1988-2003).
Access Terms
Ettore Majorana Centre for Scientific Culture.; Harvard Medical School.; International Conference on Magnetic Resonance in Biological Systems.; Jardetzky, Oleg.; Stanford University. Nuclear Magnetic Resonance Laboratory.; Stanford University. School of Medicine--Faculty.; World Federation of Scientists.; Nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Harvard University
    - Harvard Years (Box 1 of 2), 1957-1967 (Box 1)
    - Harvard Years (Box 2 of 2), 1957-1967 (Box 2)
    - Harvard Years NIH and NSF, 1957-1967 (Box 3)
  - Stanford-Dept of Molecular Pharmacology
    - Committee on Courses and Curriculum/Lectures and Teaching, Undated (Box 4)
    - Faculty Affairs (Box 1 of 2), Undated (Box 5)
    - Faculty Affairs (Box 2 of 2), Undated (Box 6)
    - Stanford Senate/Indirect Cost Crisis/Pharmacology Crisis, Undated (Box 7)
  - Stanford-Stanford Magnetic Resonance Laboratory (SMRL)
    - Administration, 1971-1982 (Box 8)
    - Administration, 1983-1998 (Box 9)
    - Grants-NSF/NIH Founding Grant/Center Grant (1 of 2), Undated (Box 10)
    - Grants-Center Grant (2 of 2)/In Vivo Grants, Undated (Box 11)
    - Grants-NIH and NSF R01 Grants, Undated (Box 12)
    - Grants-Trp Repessor and other small grants, Undated (Box 13)
    - SMRL Personnel A-G, Undated (Box 14)
    - SMRL Personnel H-M, Undated (Box 15)
    - SMRL Personnel N-Z, Undated (Box 16)
    - SMRL User Correspondence and Proposal Forms, Undated (Box 17)
    - SMRL Core Research and Collaborations (1 of 2), Undated (Box 18)
    - SMRL Collaborations (2 of 2), Undated (Box 19)
    - Correspondence, 1970-1983 (Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1984-1991 (Box 21)
    - Correspondence, 1992-2001 (Box 22)
    - Correspondence, A-L, Undated (Box 23)
    - Correspondence, M-Z, Undated (Box 24)
  - Professional Activities
    - Instrumentation Funding/Association for Advanced Technology in Biomedical Sciences (AATBS) (Box 1 of 2), Undated (Box 25)
    - Instrumentation Funding/AATBS (Box 2 of 2), Undated (Box 26)
    - International Conference on Magnetic Resonance in Biological Systems (ICMRBS), 1964-1982 (Box 27)
    - ICMRBS, 1984-2002 (Box 28)
    - ICMRBS International Conference 1982/Oleg Jardetzky Birthday Symposium, 1982-1994 (Box 29)
    - International Society for Magnetic Resonance (ISMAR) (Box 1 of 2), Undated (Box 30)
    - International Society for Magnetic Resonance (ISMAR) (Box 2 of 2), Undated (Box 31)
    - World Federation of Scientists (WFS)/Ettore Majorana Centre for Scientific Culture, 1988-1989 (Box 32)
    - World Federation of Scientists (WFS)/Ettore Majorana Centre for Scientific Culture, 1993-1997 (Box 33)
    - World Federation of Scientists (WFS)/Ettore Majorana Centre for Scientific Culture, 1998-2003 (Box 34)
    - Professional Activities, 1967-1971 (Box 35)
    - Professional Activities, 1972-1979 (Box 36)
    - Professional Activities, 1980-1986 (Box 37)
    - Professional Activities, 1987-1994 (Box 38)
    - Professional Activities, 1994-2001 (Box 39)